# Mohamed Hasabou

E-Mail Address : mho.elsayed@hotmail.com

Mobile Telephone No : +48 / 732 995 045 Google DUO : +2 / 011 530 771 92

Nationality : Egyptian / Resident in Krakow-Poland Address : Ul. Mogliska, 123/23 Krakow -Poland

**Objective** : General Manager

## **Professional Skills and Management style:**

- \* Professional, well organized person and hands-on approach hardworking
- \* Appropriate business acumen thereby maximizing GOP and Protecting assets and investments
- \* A sales focus to drive business levels with a commercial approach
- \* Maintaining and maximizing owner relations
- \* Creating a consumer environment and drive guest loyalty
- \* Creating and maintaining a motivational, peak performing environment for employees
- \* Act as an ambassador of Responsible Business
- \* Opening experience, several big Hotels and Resorts
- \* Superb F&B management skill & Strong Food & Beverage knowledge
- \* Manage with highly achievements
- \* Creative marketing & concept strategist with a large banqueting experience
- \* Coaching and mentoring with a sharp time table
- \* Excellent Team builder, Team player, and good motivator
- \* Proactive attitude, cooperative, open minded, Excellent in communications, business focus
- \* Customer-oriented with attention to details and Capable solve any problem
- \* Flexible, able to work under pressure and able to multi task in fast-paced environment
- \* Strong financial knowledge in costs and expenses
- \* Experience in budget and FF&E preparation as well as P&L written and verbal
- \* Menu engineering, restaurant development
- \* Ability to lead a different nationality of the staff with Strong and excellent leadership skills
- \* Excellent trainer and guiding front and back of the house
- \*Computer User to support my profession with all the programs
- \*Experienced in implementation and maintaining HACCP and FOOD SAFETY
- \* Speaking 4 languages: Arabic, English, French, Italian and basics of Polish, German and Russian
- \* Well familiar with Hausa, Yoruba, Ebo, African tongues,

#### **Achievements:**

I made opening three times for three big hotels plus several 5 stars restaurants.

Experienced with high knowledge in Rooms division, Engineering, F&B and Kitchen, Accounts, H.k, F.O, Well understanding and problems solving with the FF&E and P&L

Highest point of Cost control as part of my responsibilities and involvement in the kitchen for presentation and food quality I achieved the Value. Not only but in all Department

Feasibility study for many new concepts (Hotels, Resorts and Restaurants)

I Create many Marketing plan and follow it with an S.W.A.T Market plan

I achieved the financial target for the room occupancy and banquets revenue,

Reducing expenses of the entire department without any affection to their performance

Succeed to train and create a very good teamwork whenever I go.

Effectiveness of training, performance evaluations followed by the KPI'S system.

Many positive guest Comments and thanks letters many positive and motivate memos from the Management Task force twice, I was one of team from three persons.



#### **EDUCATION and TRAINING COURSES**

- \* Well trained and practicing on the COVID 19 Protocol.
- \*eCornell's Certificate in Hospitality Management (end not yet)
- \* Hotel Management with I C S American School
- \*Industrial Technical Institute –Alexandria
- \* Highly following up the Safety ways of "EBOLA"
- \* Train the trainer (American Hotel &Lodging Educational institute)
- \*Attend the conference of the Bird Flu Tourism Investment Association (Red Sea)
- \* Check Food Safety first, Course with Cristal Middle East
- \* Two times one of the Crises management team (During the problems of Luxor and Sharm El-Shiekh)
- \* Official Safety Training Course, with certificate.
- \* Start in Oberoi with no certificate 1988 (Fire training, Service and Kitchen training, Hygiene Course & HACCP)

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

*Hotels	&	Rest	taura	nts	U	pera	tion	Consultant
			_					

*Hotels & Restaurants Operation Consultant Company in Krakow-Poland (AM invest)	2010	to	2020
* General Manager Cirios Hotels Ltd Nigeria (Hotels Management Company)	2012	to	2014
*E.A. Manager 5 Stars Grand Sky Resort	2009	to	2010
*Asst. F&B Manger Citadel Azur Hurghada-Sahl Hashish 5*	2008	to	2009
*F&B Manager Pyramisa Sahel Hasheesh 5 StarsLTI Pyramisa Sahel Hasheesh	2007	to	2008
*F&B Manager Beach Resort, Alexandria 4 StarsParadise Inn Group, Alexandria Egypt	2007	to	2007
*F&B Manager Badawia Resort Marsa Allam	2006	to	2007
*F&B Manager Princess Palace Hotel & Friendship Village 4 StarsAKA InternationalHurghada-Egypt	2005	to	2006
*F&B Manager Sol Melia Hotels& Resortin Egypt Sol SharmHotel, Sharm El-Sheikh, Egypt Opening Melia Pharaoh Hotel& Resort, Hurghada Egypt Opening	1997	to	2005

Melia Pharaoh Hotel& Resort, Hurghada Egypt Opening

### THE MANAGEMENT COMMENT & THE CLIENT COMMENT

Recommend letter from General Manager of Oberoi Hotel & the Grand Hotel plus Sonesta Hotel & thanks letter from Ex. General Manager of Melia Pharaoh Hotel, thanks letter from the General Manager of Sol Sharm and thanks letter from the Head Office of Sol Melia as well, also thanks letter from Ex. General Manager of the Princess Palace Hotel. Thanks letter from the Chain Des Rotisseurs,

Thanks letter from the area General Manager of Aka International

#### **REFERENCES**

Up to your request